# Shigeru Imai

124 Ferry Street Apt 211, Troy, NY 12180 (518)428-8870, shigeru.imail@gmail.com https://imais.github.io

# **SUMMARY**

Post-doctoral researcher with a demonstrated publication record of cloud computing research. Skilled in cloud resource management (Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud), performance modeling of distributed data processing applications, benchmark automation, time-series analysis, and resource scheduling.

### **EDUCATION**

# Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY

Ph.D.Computer ScienceGPA 3.73May 2018M.S. Computer ScienceGPA 3.72May 2012

Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Computer Algorithms, Operating Systems, Programming Languages, Computability and Complexity, Cloud Computing, Network Programming, Database Systems, Parallel Computing, Interactive Arts Programming, Bioinformatics & Computational Biology.

# **SKILLS**

Programming languages: Java, C, Python, SQL, JavaScript, Octave, Bash Data processing frameworks: Apache Storm, Spark, Hadoop, Kafka Domain-specific programming language design and development: JavaCC

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Post-doctoral Researcher

June 2018 - Present

Department of Computer Science, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY

• Research a geo-distributed data processing framework

Research Assistant June 2012 - May 2018

Department of Computer Science, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY

- Researched a cost-efficient cloud computing resource management framework and saved up to 49% cost compared to a conventional static scheduling technique
- Researched a new programming language for spatio-temporal data streaming applications to facilitate the development of smarter flight systems (local news exposures: Troy Record, Albany Times Union)

#### Software Engineering Intern

June 2016 - August 2016

Onshape, Inc., Cambridge, MA

- Assisted in building data warehouse software containing large volumes of metrics data
- Analyzed collected metrics data using a web-based visualization tool
- Worked in a team of about 15 people with agile software development style

#### Research Assistant

June 2014 - August 2014

Department of Science and Technology Studies, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Troy, NY

• Integrated a 3D system functionality into the C-Snap visual programming platform using three js

### SELECTED PUBLICATIONS (Google Scholar, Full publication list)

# **Cloud Computing**

- Shigeru Imai, Stacy Patterson, and Carlos A. Varela. "Uncertainty-Aware Elastic Virtual Machine Scheduling for Stream Processing Systems," In 18th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Cluster, Cloud and Grid Computing (CCGrid 2018), Washington, DC, May 2018.
- Shigeru Imai, Stacy Patterson, and Carlos A. Varela. "Maximum Sustainable Throughput Prediction for Data Stream Processing over Public Clouds," In 17th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Cluster, Cloud and Grid Computing (CCGrid 2017), Madrid, Spain, May 2017.
- 3. Shigeru Imai, Stacy Patterson, and Carlos A. Varela. "Cost-Efficient Elastic Stream Processing Using Application-Agnostic Performance Prediction," In 16th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Cluster, Cloud and Grid Computing (CCGrid 2016): Doctoral Symposium, Cartagena, Colombia, May 2016. Best Doctoral Symposium Paper Award.
- 4. Shigeru Imai, Thomas Chestna, and Carlos A. Varela. "Accurate Resource Prediction for Hybrid IaaS Clouds Using Workload-Tailored Elastic Compute Units," In 6th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Utility and Cloud Computing (UCC 2013). Dresden, Germany, December 2013.
- Shigeru Imai, Thomas Chestna, and Carlos A. Varela, "Elastic Scalable Cloud Computing Using Application-Level Migration," in 5th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Utility and Cloud Computing (UCC 2012). Chicago, Illinois, USA, November 2012.

### Air Flight Safety

- Shigeru Imai, Erik Blasch, Alessandro Galli, Wennan Zhu, Frederick Lee, and Carlos A. Varela.
  "Airplane Flight Safety Using Error-Tolerant Data Stream Processing," *IEEE Aerospace and Electronics Systems Magazine*, 32(4), 2017.
- Shigeru Imai, Sida Chen, Wennan Zhu, and Carlos A. Varela. "Dynamic Data-Driven Learning for Self-Healing Avionics," *Cluster Computing*, November 2017, ISSN:1573-7543.
- 3. **Shigeru Imai**, Richard Klockowski, and Carlos A. Varela. "Self-Healing Spatio-Temporal Data Streams Using Error Signatures," *In 2nd International Conference on Big Data Science and Engineering (BDSE 2013)*. Sydney, Australia, December 2013.

# AWARDS/HONORS

- The Robert McNaughton Prize, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (2018)
  - The prize is given to an outstanding Ph.D. student in the Computer Science Department at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute
- Amazon Web Services Cloud Credits for Research (2011-2012, 2013-2015, 2016-2018)
- CCGrid Student Travel Grant (2015, 2017, 2018)
- Yamada Corporation Fellowship, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (2012 2013)
- ACM SIGSPATIAL International Conference Student Travel Grant (2012)